Edward Butscher Collection of papers on Sylvia Plath, 1918-1976
Mortimer Rare Book Room, William Allan Neilson Library, Smith College
Edward Butscher Collection of papers on Sylvia Plath
1918-1976
1946-1976
Edward Butscher (collector)
2
6 boxes (2.5 linear ft.)
Mortimer Rare Book Room Smith College Northampton, MA
Teacher and writer from New York. Includes Butscher's correspondence about Plath and typescripts of his biographies, copies of some of Plath's correspondence, writings, and family documents, critical essays about Plath, and photographs.
Edward Butscher was born in Flushing, New York, on September 30, 1943 to Edward J. and Lena Cutillo Butscher. He was educated at Queens College of the City University of New York (B.A., 1963), Long Island University (M.A., 1971), and New York University (Ph.D.) In addition to teaching English at several public schools in New York, Butscher was a member of the faculty at the New School for Social Research (1974) and an instructor at C. W. Post Center of Long Island University (1977-78).
His writings include Sylvia Plath: Method and Madness (Seabury, 1976); Poems about Silence (Seabury, 1976); (editor) Sylvia Plath: The Woman and the Work (Dodd, 1977); Adelaid Crapsey (Twayne, 1979); (poems) Amagansett Cycle (Cross-Cultural Communications, 1979); Conrad Aiken: A Literary Biography (Dodd, 1980); (poems) Unfinished Sequence (Cross-Cultural Communications, c1981); Faces on the Barroom Floor (Contemporary Press, 1984); (editor) Paul Bowles Issue (Hofstra University Press, 1981); Conrad Aiken: Poet of White Horse Vale (University of Georgia Press, c1988); (poems) Eros Descending (Dusty Dog Chapbook, 1992); Peter Wild (Boise State University, c 1992).
The Edward Butscher Collection of papers on Sylvia Plath contains Butscher's correspondence about Plath as well as copies of some of Plath's correspondence, writings, and family documents all of which were used by Butscher to write Sylvia Plath: Method and Madness (New York: Seabury Press, 1976). In addition to Butscher's research notes and drafts of his critical biography, the papers also contain critical essays about Plath, which Butscher collected and edited as Sylvia Plath: The Woman and the Work (New York: Dodd, Mead & Company, 1977). The papers span the dates 1918-1976, but the bulk of the material covers the years 1946-1976. The papers were purchased from the House of Books, Ltd. in the late 1970s and presented to the Smith College Library Rare Book Room on July 2, 1992 by Ann Lee O'Connell Anderson, Class of 1955, and Mary Lee O'Connell Jamieson, Class of 1958, in honor of Helen Mary Lee O'Connell, Class of 1931.
Edward Butscher's correspondence is housed in Boxes 1-2, and consists of 221 letters (mostly addressed to Butscher) about Sylvia Plath and her family. Many letters refer to interviews with Butscher. Tapes of these interviews are not part of the papers. A few of Butscher's responses to Olwyn Hughes (the literary executor of the Sylvia Plath estate) are interfiled in Box 1, folder 30. John Press's memoir of Sylvia Plath is enclosed with his letters (Box 2, folder 61). A memoir of Assia Wevill is included with Edward Lucie-Smith's May 14, 1975 letter (Box 1, folder 44). Ted Hughes is also mentioned in Elizabeth Sigmund's correspondence (Box 2, folder 72). Information about Otto Plath's college degree may be found with Butscher's letters from Northwestern College (Box 2, folder 53). Mary Ellen Chase's letter of recommendation for Sylvia Plath to teach at Smith College is filed separately (Box 2, folder 88). A transcript of Aurelia Plath's July 23 1953 letter to Marcia Brown Stem describes Sylvia's health before her suicide attempt. A later letter to Elizabeth Sigmund discusses Mrs. Plath's grandchildren. All of the 54 letters in Sylvia Plath's correspondence are copies or transcripts; some concern her student days at Smith College, while a few deal with her later appointment to the English Department at Smith College. Both sides of her correspondence with John Lehmann about writing submissions to The London Magazine are contained in Box 2, folder 95. Scholars should write directly to the University of Texas at Austin to see copies of these letters.
The original typescript of Butscher's biography of Sylvia Plath is housed in Box 3. Galleys may be found in Box 4, along with the objections and corrections of Olwyn Hughes, Philip McCurdy, and Warren J. Plath. Only three essays for Sylvia Plath: The Woman and the Work are represented by typescripts in the papers. Of the 168 examples of Sylvia Plath's writing, only the essay "Snow Blitz" (Box 5, folder 136) is an original typescript and it was "supplied by Olwyn Hughes." Otherwise, Plath's thesis, poetry, essays, and short stories are printed versions or photocopies from the original manuscripts at the Lilly Library, Humanities Research Center at the University of Texas at Austin, and Smith College. In addition, there are some fragments of Letters Home and a copy of the radio script for "Three Woman. " The sixteen pieces about Sylvia Plath are copies of printed articles, except for a poem by Peter Davison, an article by Gordon Lameyer, and an excerpt from Marcia Brown Stern's diary.
Besides clippings, Other Papers (46 items) contains copies of Sylvia Plath's death certificate and obituaries, a few of her college notes, and copies of the Plath-Schober family documents, such as death certificates.
A group of fifteen photographs of Sylvia Plath, friends, and places she lived complete the papers. Many of these photographs were reproduced by Butscher in Sylvia Plath: Method and Madness.
This collection is organized into four series:
I. Correspondence (1951-1976)
II. Writings (1944-1976)
III. Other Papers (1918-1974)
IV. Photographs (1949-1962)
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The Edward Butscher Collection of papers on Sylvia Plath are the physical property of the Smith College Library Rare Book Room. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors of works or their legal representatives.
Photocopies in the papers may not be duplicated and permission to quote from them must be obtained from the owner of the original manuscript as well as the copyright holder.
History of the Collection
The papers were purchased from the House of Books, Ltd. in the late 1970s and presented to the Smith College Library Rare Book Room on July 2, 1992 by Ann Lee O'Connell Anderson, Class of 1955, and Mary Lee O'Connell Jamieson, Class of 1958, in honor of Helen Mary Lee O'Connell, Class of 1931.
Plath's thesis, poetry, essays, and short stories are printed versions or photocopies from the original manuscripts at the Lilly Library, Humanities Research Center at the University of Texas at Austin, and Smith College.
Search Terms
Butscher, Edward; Davison, Peter; Hughes, Olwyn; Krook, Dorothea; McCurdy, Philip; Plath, Aurelia Schober; Roche, Clarissa; Sigmund, Elizabeth; Plath, Sylvia--Biography; Poets, American--20th century--Biography
- Series I. Correspondence, 1951-76, 1' (278 items)
  Boxes 1-2 holds series 1, Correspondence, which is divided into the correspondence of Edward Butscher, Mary Ellen Chase, Aurelia Plath, and Sylvia Plath. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and then chronologically.
- Series II. Writings, 1945-75, 1' (217 items)
  Boxes 3-6 hold series II, Writings, which is divided into the writings of Edward Butscher, Sylvia Plath, and writings About Sylvia Plath.
- Series III. Other Papers, 1918-74, .25' (46 items)
  Box 6 holds series III, Other Papers, which is arranged alphabetically by type of material.
- Series IV. Photographs, 1949-62, .25' (15 items)
  Box 6 holds series IV, Photographs.
- Series I. Correspondence, 1951-76
  - EDWARD BUTSCHER (221 items)
    - Abels, Cyrilly (6 items) 1973-74 (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Anderson, Robert E., Jr. (2 items) 1973 Aug 10 (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Bailey, Norman S. (3 items) 1972-73 (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Baldwin, Francis E. (1 item) 1972 Nov 16 (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Barnhouse, Ruth T. (I item) 1972 Nov 28 (Box-folder 1:5)
    - Baskin, Leonard (I item) 1975 Feb 26 (Box-folder 1:6)
    - Botsford, Marion
      See: Rydell, Barbara
    - Bradbury, Malcolm (1 item) 1973 May 14 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation (2 items) 1969-73 (Box-folder 1:8)
    - British Library (1 item) 1973 Oct 16 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - Burton, Kay (4 items) 1972-74 (Box-folder 1:10)
    - Cahill, Linda (I item) 1972 Oct 3 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - Cambridge University (4 items) 1972-73 (Box-folder 1:12)
    - Cohn, Marge (2 items) 1975 Apr-May (Box-folder 1:13)
    - Compton, David (1 item) 1975 May 1 (Box-folder 1:14)
    - Craig, Anna C. (I item) 1972 Nov 14 (Box-folder 1:15)
    - Crockett, Wilbury (6 items) 1969-73 (Box-folder 1:16)
    - Davis, Robert G. (1 item) 1972 Dec 11 (Box-folder 1:17)
    - Davison, Peter and Jane (5 items) 1973-74 (Box-folder 1:18)
    - Duncan, Stewart (1 item) 1973 Mar 1 (Box-folder 1:19)
    - Faber and Faber Ltd. (1 item) 1973 Apr 11 (Box-folder 1:20)
    - Fainlight, Ruth (2 items) 1973-74 (Box-folder 1:21)
    - Fulton, George P. (1 item) 1972 Nov 20 (Box-folder 1:22)
    - Gibian, George (4 items) 1972-73 (Box-folder 1:23)
    - Giesey, Mary L. (1 item) 1972 Nov 14 (Box-folder 1:24)
    - Grossman, Allen (I item) 1969 Apr 6 (Box-folder 1:25)
    - Harvard University (4 items) 1972-73 (Box-folder 1:26)
    - Henry, Clement Moore (2 items) 1972-73 (Box-folder 1:27)
    - Hirt, Howard (I item) n. y. Feb 14 (Box-folder 1:28)
    - Huggins, Gail E. (1 item) 1972 Oct 1 (Box-folder 1:29)
    - Hughes, Olwyn (26 items) 1972-75 (Box-folder 1:30)
    - Humphrey, Dorothy H. (1 item) 1973 Jan 4 (Box-folder 1:31)
    - Indiana University (2 items) 1973 Nov-Dec (Box-folder 1:32)
    - Irish, Frank and Laura (4 items) 1972-73 (Box-folder 1:33)
    - Kahrl, Stanley J. (2 items) 1974 May (Box-folder 1:34)
    - Kazin, Alfred (1 item) 1972 Oct 13 (Box-folder 1:35)
    - Kopp, Jane (5 items) 1972-73 (Box-folder 1:36)
    - Krook, Dorothea (4 items) 1972-74 (Box-folder 1:37)
    - Kunitz, Stanley (1 item) 1973 Jun-Aug (Box-folder 1:38)
    - Lameyer, Gordon (4 items) 1973-74 (Box-folder 1:39)
    - Lape, James T. (3 items) 1969-72 (Box-folder 1:40)
    - Lawson, Helen L. (3 items) 1972-74 (Box-folder 1:41)
    - Lind, Louise T. (1 item) 1972 Dec 4 (Box-folder 1:42)
    - Lotz, Myron (7 items) 1972-74 (Box-folder 1:43)
    - Lucie-Smith, Edward (4 items) 1973-75 (Box-folder 1:44)
    - MacBeth, George (3 items) 1973-74 (Box-folder 1:45)
    - McCullough, Frances (I item) 1973 Apr 11 (Box-folder 1:46)
    - McCurdy, Philip E. (9 items) 1972-75 (Box-folder 1:47)
    - McLean Hospital (I item) 1972 Nov 16 (Box-folder 1:48)
    - Mademoiselle (1 item) 1973 Jul 10 (Box-folder 1:49)
    - Miller, Jonathan (I item) 1973 Jul 20 (Box-folder 1:50)
    - Modlin, Robert K. (2 items) 1973 Jul-Aug (Box-folder 1:51)
    - Moore, Clement
      See: Henry, Clement Moore
    - Nevada (4 items) 1974 Jun-Jul (Box-folder 2:52)
      See also: Box 6, folder 158
    - Northwestern College (2 items) 1974 May-Jun (Box-folder 2:53)
    - Northwestern University (1 item) 1974 Mar 14 (Box-folder 2:54)
    - Norton, C. Perry, Richard, Shirley, and William B. (8 items) 1972-74 (Box-folder 2:55)
    - Oregon (2 items) 1974 May-Jun (Box-folder 2:56)
    - Orton, Ora Mae (2 items) 1973 Sep-Nov (Box-folder 2:57)
    - Oxford University (2 items) 1973 Aug-Sep (Box-folder 2:58)
    - Pitt, Valerie (1 item) 1972 Dec 11 (Box-folder 2:59)
    - Plath, Aurelia S. (5 items) 1969-74 (Box-folder 2:60)
    - Press, John (2 items) 1974 Jan-Apr (Box-folder 2:61)
    - Prouty, Olive H. (1 item) 1976 Oct 25 (Box-folder 2:62)
    - Public Library of Brookline (1 item) 1973 Oct 16 (Box-folder 2:63)
    - Rafferty, Janet Wagner (2 items) 1974 Apr-May (Box-folder 2:64)
    - Rosenthal, M.L. (I item) 1974 Jun 18 (Box-folder 2:65)
    - Rydell, Barbara (3 items) 1972-73 (Box-folder 2:66)
    - Sachar, Neva (1 item) 1974 Jan 9 (Box-folder 2:67)
    - Salter, Elizabeth (2 items) 1973-74 (Box-folder 2:68)
    - Schendler, Sylvan (2 items) 1973 Feb-Dec (Box-folder 2:69)
    - Selvin, Rhoda (1 item) 1973 Dec 13 (Box-folder 2:70)
    - Shapiro, Norman (1 item) 1972 Dec 12 (Box-folder 2:71)
    - Sigmund, Elizabeth (5 items) 1974 Jan-Dec (Box-folder 2:72)
    - Small, Verna (1 item) 1973 Oct 21 (Box-folder 2:73)
    - Smith College (3 items) 1971-72 (Box-folder 2:74)
    - Stem, Marcia Brown (2 items) 1974 Mar-Nov (Box-folder 2:75)
    - Steuble, Richard (1 item) 1973 Nov 17 (Box-folder 2:76)
    - Targett, May (2 items) 1973 Jan-Aug (Box-folder 2:77)
    - The Times Literary Supplement (1 item) 1972 Oct 19 (Box-folder 2:78)
    - University of Texas. Humanities Research Center (2 items) 1972-73 (Box-folder 2:79)
    - University of Washington (1 item) 1973 Oct 15 (Box-folder 2:80)
    - Washington University Libraries (2 items) 1973 Jan-Feb (Box-folder 2:81)
    - Wellesley Free Library (1 item) 1973 Sep 18 (Box-folder 2:82)
    - Willard, Addie L. (1 item) 1974 Jul 31 (Box-folder 2:83)
    - Winthrop, Massachusetts (4 items) 1974 Jun-Aug (Box-folder 2:84)
    - Witten, Mrs. Robert C. (1 item) 1974 Jan 15 (Box-folder 2:85)
    - Wober, Mallery (1 item) 1972 Nov 25 (Box-folder 2:86)
    - Yaddo (1 item) 1972 Nov 27 (Box-folder 2:87)
    - Zavadil, Joseph B.
      See: Kopp, Jane
  - MARY ELLEN CHASE
    - Davis, Robert G. (1 item) [1957] Feb 3 (Box-folder 2:88)
  - AURELIA SCHOBER PLATH
    - Sigmund, Elizabeth (1 item) 1967 Jan 29 (Box-folder 2:89)
    - Stem, Marcia Brown (1 item) 1953 Jul 23 (Box-folder 2:90)
  - SYLVIA PLATH
    - Aaron, Daniel (1 item) 1957 Jun 11 (Box-folder 2:91)
    - Brown, Marcia
      See: Stem, Marcia Brown
    - Davis, Robert G. (5 items) 1956-57 (Box-folder 2:92)
    - Hughes, Olwyn (1 item) 1962 Jan (Box-folder 2:93)
    - Kopp, Jane (1 item) 1958 Feb 20 (Box-folder 2:94)
    - Lehmann, John (18 items) 1955-63 (Box-folder 2:95)
      (Restricted access)
    - McCurdy, Philip (9 items) 1954 Feb-May (Box-folder 2:96)
    - Osborne, Charles
      See: Lehmann, John
    - Stem, Marcia Brown (19 items) 1951-63 (Box-folder 2:97)
  - WARREN J. PLATH
    - Shields, Margot (editor, Seabury Press)
      See: Box 4, folder 120
- Series II. Writings, 1945-75
  - EDWARD BUTSCHER
    - Sylvia Plath: Method and Madness
      - Research notes (20 items) undated (Box-folder 3:98)
      - Typescript, with author's corrections 1975 Jan (Box-folder 3:99-106)
      - Typescript (photocopy) 1975 Jan (Box-folder 3-4:107-114)
      - Preface: later typescript undated (Box-folder 4:115)
      - "Insert A": typescript undated (Box-folder 4:116)
      - Galleys, bound, with author's corrections 1975 Jul (Box-folder 4:117)
      - Corrections of Olwyn Hughes undated (Box-folder 4:118)
        See also: Box 1, folder 30
      - Corrections of Philip McCurdy 1975 Feb 4-11 (Box-folder 4:119)
        See also: Box 1, folder 47
      - Corrections of Warren J. Plath 1975 Aug 31 (Box-folder 4:120)
    - Sylvia Plath: The Woman and the Work
      - Krook, Dorothea. "Recollections of Sylvia Plath": typescript, carbon, with corrections 1974 Aug 4 (Box-folder 4:121)
        See also: Box 1, folder 37
      - Roche, Clarissa. "Sylvia Plath: Vignettes from England": typescript undated (Box-folder 4:122)
      - Sigmund, Elizabeth. "Sylvia in Devon, 1962": typescript, corrected undated (Box-folder 4:123)
  - SYLVIA PLATH
    - Letters Home (book)
      - Preface: typescript undated (Box-folder 5:124)
      - Fragments 1974 Sep 6 (Box-folder 5:125)
      - Part seven: typescript (photocopy) 1975 Nov 1 (Box-folder 5:126)
    - Poems A-D (29 items)
      - "Admonition": 2 typescripts, photocopies undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "Advice for an Artificer": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "Apparel for April": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "Apprehensions"
        See: "Babysitters"
      - "April": typescript, photocopy 1947 May (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "Aquatic Nocturne": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "The Babysitters": photocopy from New Yorker undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "Bereft": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "Black Rook in Rainy Weather": photocopy from Granta 1957 May (Box-folder 5:127)
        See also: "The Surgeon at 2 A.M."
      - "The Bronze Boy": photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "By Candlelight"
        See: "The Babysitters"
      - "Carnival": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "Carnival Nocturne": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "Circus in Three Rings": typescript, photocopy 1951-52 (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "City Streets": typescript, photocopy 1947 Nov (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "City Wife": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "Click-click; Tick-tick": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "The Complex Couch": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "The Courage of Shutting Up"
      - "Danse Macabre": 2 typescripts, photocopies undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "The Dark River": typescript, photocopy 1948 (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "The Dead": typescript and typescript, photocopy 1954 (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "The Death of Myth Making"
        See: "On the Decline of Oracles"
      - "Denouement": 2 typescripts, photocopies undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "Dialogue en Route": 2 typescripts, photocopies 1953-55 (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "Dirge": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "Dirge for a Joker": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "The Dispossessed": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:127)
      - "Dream with Clam-Diggers"
        See: "Resolve"
    - Poems E-I (27 items)
      - "Eavesdropper"
        See: "Purdah"
      - "Elegy": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Elizabeth": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Ennui": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Epitaph in Three Parts": typescript, photocopy 1955 (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Eve Describes Her Birthday Party": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Face Lift"
        See: "Stars Over the Dordogne"
      - "Family Reunion"
        See: "The Farewell"
      - "The Farewell": typescript, photocopy and photocopy from The Bradford 1950 Apr 29 (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Finality": typescript, copy undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Fireside Reveries": photocopy of The Phillipian 1947 Feb (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Fog": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "For a Fatherless Son"
      - "Go Get the Goodly Squab": typescript, photocopy 1953 Apr (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Gone Is the River": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Harlequin Love Song": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Have You Forgotten?": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Heavy Woman"
      - "Humoresque": typescript, copy undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "I Have Found the Perfect World": typescript, photocopy 1948 (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "I Reach Out": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "I Thought That I Could Not Be Hurt": typescript, photocopy 1947 May 30 (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Ice Age": 2 typescripts, photocopies undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "In Memorium": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "In Passing": 2 typescripts undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Incident": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Insolent Storm Strikes at the Skull": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "The Invalid": typescript, photocopy 1950 (Box-folder 5:128)
      - "Item: Stolen, One Suitcase": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:128)
    - Poems J-0 (21 items)
      - "Jilted": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "Lament": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "Latvian Threnody": typescript, with drawing, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "A Lesson in Vengeance"
      - "Let the Rain Fall Gently": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "Love Is a Parallax": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "Love Letter"
      - "Mad Girl's Love Song": photocopy from Granta 1957 May (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "March"
        See: "The Spring Parade"
      - "May": typescript, photocopy 1947 May 15 (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "Metamorphoses of the Moon": typescript photocopy 1953 (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "Moonsong at Morning": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "Morning in the Hospital Solarium": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "Neither Moonlight Nor Starlight": typescript, photocopy 1948 (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "Never Try to Know More Than You Should": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "New England Library": typescript, photocopy 1947 May (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "New England Winter Without Snow": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "Notes on Zarathustra's Prologue": typescript, photocopy 1950-51 (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "November Graveyard": photocopy from Mademoiselle 1965 Nov (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "Obsession": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "October"
        See: "To Miss Cox"
      - "Ode on a Bitten Plum": typescript, photocopy, and photocopy from Seventeen 1950 Nov (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "On Looking into the Eyes of a Demon Lover": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:129)
      - "On the Decline of Oracles": photocopy from Poetry 1959 Sep (Box-folder 5:129)
    - Poems P-R (16 items)
      - "Parallax": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:130)
      - "Persecuted": typescript, photocopy 1948 (Box-folder 5:130)
      - "Pheasant"
      - "Portrait": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:130)
      - "Portrait d'une Jeune Fille": typescript, photocopy 1949 (Box-folder 5:130)
      - "Prologue to Spring": 3 typescripts, photocopies undated (Box-folder 5:130)
      - "Purdah": photocopy from Poetry 1963 Aug (Box-folder 5:130)
      - "Question": photocopy from The Bradford 1949 Oct 27 (Box-folder 5:130)
      - "Rain": typescript, photocopy 1944 (Box-folder 5:130)
      - "The Rain": photocopy 1945 Jun (Box-folder 5:130)
      - "Recognition": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:130)
      - "Reflection": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:130)
      - "Resolve": photocopy from Granta 1957 Mar (Box-folder 5:130)
      - "Riddle": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:130)
      - "Rondeau": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:130)
    - Poems S (18 items)
      - "The Scullion's Dream": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "Sea Symphony": photocopy from The Phillipian 1947 Apr (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "Second Winter": typescript, photocopy 1953 (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "The Sleepers": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "The Snowflake Star"
        See: "A Winter Sunset"
      - "Soliloquy of the Solipsist"
        See: "Mad Girl's Love Song"
      - "Song of the Daydreamer": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "Sonnet: Crossing the Equinox": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "Sonnet to a Dissembling Spring": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "Sonnet to a Shade": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "Sonnet to Time": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "Sorrow": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "Spinster": photocopy from Gemini 1957 spring (Box-folder 5:131)
      - "Spring Again": typescript, photocopy undated (Box-folder 5:131)